You must be happy, Issho...
،لا بدّ أنك سعيدٌ يا إيشو
Abolishing the Seven Warlords was what you all wanted.
.فقد كانت غايتك إلغاء نظام الشيتشيبوكاي
I was against it, but we must abide by the sovereigns' decision.
.لا بد من التقيد بقرار الملوك وإن كنتُ معارضًا له
Dammit! How can they all be so naive?!
!سُحقًا، ما مدى سذاجة الجميع؟
Justice comes with a price–
...للعدالة ثمن دائمًا
And there's no other way?
ولا مهرب منها؟
You can't understand because you've never been one of them...
...لن تفهم لأنّك لم تكن يومًا واحدًا منهم
A world where the weak and innocent are disregarded is worthless!
!لا قيمة لعالم يُهمَل فيه الضعاف الأبرياء
Hurry up! Keep moving!
!بسرعة! واصلوا التّقدّم
Hurry!
!أسرعوا
The Seven Warlords of the Sea are no more.
.لم يعد للشيتشيبوكاي أي أثر
Let's have faith in the SSG, the Marines' Special Science Group.
«لنضع ثقتنا في فرقة البحريّة العلميّة الخاصّة «ب ع خ
The world's balance of power is about to shift drastically!
،توازن القوى في العالم على مشارف تغيير جذريّ
But we don't know how it'll change!
!لكننا نجهل مسار ذلك التّغيير
Word is that Kaido and Big Mom are forming an alliance in Wano!
...سمعتُ أنّ كايدو وبيغ مام قد تحالفا في بلاد وانو
What?!
!ماذا؟
Could it mean the return of the Rocks?!
!ألا يعني هذا عودة الروكس؟
Don't speak of it like it's just some legend!
!لا تتحدّث عنهم وكأنّهم أسطورة أو ما شابه
It's all true...
...كل ما يُشاع عنهم حقيقي
and it's a disaster that menaces us despite how preoccupied we are!
!في شدة إنشغالنا تأتي الكوارث تباعًا
What?! Two Emperors joined forces?!
!ماذا؟! تحالَف إمبراطوريْن؟
No way!
!مُحال
Now of all times?!
!وفي وقت كهذا؟
More accurately, intelligence indicates they'll team up in the coming days.
...بشكل أدقّ، وصلتنا معلومات أنّ تحالفهما مزمع في الأيّام القادمة
They haven't done any harm so far, and we don't know their objective or how to deal with it yet.
.لم يتسبّبا بأضرار فعليّة حتى الآن ونجهل هدفهما وكيفية مواجهتهما
The only thing that connects those two is...
...الشّيء الوحيد المشترك بينهما
the legendary Rocks Pirates.
.هو قراصنة الروكس الأسطوريّون
But there isn't much information about them, either...
...لكن معلوماتنا شحيحة عنهما أيضًا
Big Mom and Kaido have hated each other for a long time...
...كرَهَ كلّ من بيغ مام وكايدو بعضهما لوقتٍ طويل
I never expected such a thing would ever happen.
تحالفهما لم يكن في الحسبان
Sengoku, who are the Rocks Pirates?
من هم الروكس يا سينغوكو-سان؟
Oh, yeah.
،صحيح
You're too young to have heard about them...
...أنتم شباب ولا علم لكم بهم
The Rocks Pirates was a crew of personalities who gathered together...
...كان قراصنة الروكس مجموعة فريدة اجتمعوا معًا
for a money-making scheme on Pirate Island, Beehive, ages ago.
سعيًا وراء منفعةٍ معينةٍ في جزيرة القراصنة هاتشينوس قبل زمن طويل
They were all so violent, they would even battle to the death on board their own ship.
كانوا طاقمًا وحشيًّا لدرجة أنهم تقاتلوا حتى الموت حتى على متن سفينتهم
Its members were, first, Captain Rocks...
...وكان يتألّف أعضاؤها من القبطان روكس
A young Whitebeard!
!واللّحية البيضاء في عزّ شبابه
Big Mom!
!وبيغ مام
And Kaido!
!وكايدو
Really?
...هذا أمرٌ لا يعقل
Those three used to serve aboard the same pirate ship.
.كان هؤلاء الثّلاثة يبحرون على متن نفس السفينة
– What?!
!ماذا؟
N-No way!
!مـ-مستحيل
I-I can't believe it!
!لا-لا أصدّق هذا
Others from the Rocks Pirates became infamous as well.
ثمّة آخرون من صفوف طاقم الروكس ذاع صيتهم لاحقًا أيضًا
Shiki the Golden Lion, a big name who vied for dominance in the New World.
.كالأسد الذّهبيّ شيكي الّذي كان مشهورًا وتنافس على سيادة العالم الجديد
There were also others like Silver Axe, Captain John, and Ochoku...
وآخرون أيضًا مثل الفأس الفضّيّة والقبطان جون وأوتشوكو
You've got to be kidding!
!لا بدّ أنّك تمزح! كلها أسماء قراصنة كبار
How was such a pirate group lost to history?
كيف لتاريخهم أن يضيع في طيّ النسيان؟
Firstly, they hated each other so much that they took no pride in publicizing their exploits.
أحد الأسباب هو كرههم الشّديد لبعضهم، كما لم يتفاخروا علنًا بإنجازاتهم
Secondly...
...إضافةً لذلك
Captain Rocks wanted to become the king of the world.
...فقد طمح القبطان روكس في أن يصير ملك العالم
They began a campaign of savage provocation against the World Government.
.لذلك كشّروا عن أنيابهم لحكومة العالم وكأنّهم منظمة إرهابيّة
Their terrorist acts too violent to suppress...
،وكانت أعمالهم الإرهابية أعنف مما يمكن التستر عليه
the world came to fear their very name.
.لكن مدى خطرهم بلغ جميع أُناس العالم حينها
A particularly fateful incident took place at God Valley thirty-eight years ago.
.وقعت حادثة مصيريّة معيّنة في وادي الإله قبل 38 عامًا
The news reported that the Rocks Pirates, known as the world's strongest pirate crew...
أفادت الأخبار أنّ قراصنة الروكس الأقوى
were annihilated on that island.
...في العالم قد أُبيدوا في تلك الجزيرة
That unstoppable force of evil was defeated...
الشر المستفحل الذي لم يكن له رادع
by Marine Headquarters' Vice Admiral Garp!
!تمكَّن نائب الأميرال غارب من تسويته بالأرض
His name became known throughout the world,
انتشر اسمه كالنار في الهشيم حول العالم
and people began calling him the Hero of the Marines.
.وعُرف بعدها ببطل البحريّة
So that's the start to Vice Admiral Garp's many tales of heroism!
!إذًا فتلك بداية قصص بطولة نائب الأميرال غارب العديدة
There are countless tales of valor involving Vice Admiral Garp,
نائب الأميرال غارب يمتلك سجلًا حافلًا بالأساطير البطولية
but I didn't know there was yet another great episode like that!
!لكنّني لم أعلم أنّ هنالك فصلًا عظيمًا آخر منها
He's really something!
!إنّه مميّز فعلًا
Big Mom and Kaido?!
!بيغ مام وكايدو؟
Enough already...
...هذا يكفي
But he generally refuses to discuss it.
.لكنه يبغض التحدث عن هذه الحادثة
What? Why?
لماذا؟
I'll fill you in so you can learn some history...
...سأطلعكم على الأمر لتكونوا ملمّين ببعض التّاريخ
The first reason he doesn't share was never reported in the papers.
...السبب الأول: لم يُذكر الأمر في أيٍّ من الصحف
Garp had no choice but to join forces with a pirate to win that battle.
.ولكن في تلك المعركة حُتم عليه أن يتعاون مع قرصان
A pirate?!
!مع قرصان؟
The other reason is he happened to save the Celestial Dragons.
.والسّبب الآخر هو أنّه حمى التّنانين السّماويّة
The Celestial Dragons were part of that story?!
التّنانين السّماويّة كانوا جزءًا من القصّة؟
Well, it is a Marine's duty to protect Celestial Dragons.
أليسَ حماية التنانين السماوية واجب على جنود البحرية؟
What's the issue here?
فما الخطب في ذلك؟
Garp is morally opposed to fulfilling that duty.
هذا الواجب ليس جزءًا من مبادئه الأخلاقية
One of the reasons Garp refuses to become an admiral...
...أحد الأسباب الّتي تدفع غارب لرفض منصب الأميرال
is that they are the direct subordinates of the Celestial Dragons.
.هو أنّ الأميرالات أتباع مباشرون للتّنانين السّماويّة
Despite openly showing contempt for them,
.إنّه يُظهر علنًا عدم الاحترام لهم، ولكن يُفصَح عنه بفضل إنجازاته وشعبيّته
Now, the truth of the matter is...
...الحقيقة خلف هذه المسألة
to protect the Celestial Dragons and their slaves at God Valley,
،من أجل حماية التّنانين السّماويّة وعبيدهم في وادي الإله
Garp worked together with Roger, who also happened to be there, to defeat the Rocks Pirates!
!فقد تعاون غارب مع روجر الّذي كان هناك لهزيمة قراصنة الروكس
It's known as the God Valley Incident!
!وهذا ما يُعرف بحادثة وادي الإله
He worked together...
...تعاون مع ملك القراصنة
and fought with...
...وقاتلا معًا
...the Pirate King?!
!جنبًا لجنب؟
The Celestial Dragons, Roger, and Rocks?!
!التّنانين السّماويّة وروجر وروكس؟
They were all there at the same time?!
!لا أصدّق أنّهم كانوا جميعًا في نفس المكان والوقت، ماذا حدث تحديدًا في تلك الجزيرة؟
I've never even heard of God Valley!
!«لم أسمع مُسبقًا عن «وادي الإله
It's no wonder.
...لا عجب في ذلك
The place called God Valley...
«بقعة الأرض المعروفة بـ«وادي الإله
is nowhere to be found on any map now.
.لم تعد موجودةً في أي خريطة حديثة
In fact, it disappeared without a trace.
...في الحقيقة، اختفت الجزيرة بلا أثر
The island that the World Government wanted to hide disappeared...
...الجزيرة الّتي أرادت حكومة العالم إخفاءها قد اختفت بلا أثر
Do you still want to hear about it?
أما زلتم تريدون معرفة المزيد عن الجزيرة؟
Rocks was so zealous in his goal to become the king of the world
،ذات مرّة، حاول روكس الطّموح أن يصير ملك العالم
that he broke one too many taboos,
...لكنّه انتهك عديدًا من المحرّمات لذلك ما عادت المعلومات متوفّرة عنه
He is remembered only by a handful of Marines from my generation.
.لم يتبّق سوى جزءٌ كامن في ذكريات أبناء جيلي من جنود البحرية
Even if it was a long time ago, I can't imagine one man leading three future Emperors!
،حتّى إن كان ذلك منذ زمن
Rocks might have been Roger's first, and strongest, foe.
...أمّا روجر، ربّما كان روكس هو أوّل وأقوى عدوّ له
Strangely enough, Roger and Rocks had something in common.
.والغريب في الأمر، كان ثمّة أمر مشترك بين روجر وروكس
Rocks' full name was Rocks D. Xebec.
.اسم روكس الكامل هو روكس دي زيبك
He's already passed on,
،مع أنّه كان قد مات سلفًا
but he was among those pirates who bear the initial D. in their name!
!إلّا أنه كان أحد القراصنة ممن يحملون اسم الدي
It's true that Kaido and Big Mom were on board the same ship...
...صحيح أنّ كايدو وبيغ مام كانا يبحران على متن نفس السّفينة
but their capabilities are totally different from thirty-eight years ago.
.لكنّ قدراتهما مختلفة بالكامل عمّا كانت عليه قبل 38 عام
If this alliance is true, we're about to see the world's most dangerous group of pirates.
.إن كانا قد تحالفا فعلًا، فنحن على وشك رؤية أخطر مجموعة قراصنة في العالم
Brannew! How much are their bounties now?
كم بلغت مكافآتهما يا برانيو؟
Ah, yes.
.صحيح، علينا الإعلان عن مكافآت جديدة للمجردين من لقب الشّيتشيبوكاي أيضًا
Let's review all of their numbers.
.لنراجع كلّ مكافآتهم
Starting with Blackbeard,
،بدءًا من اللحية السوداء
who started to be called an Emperor about a year ago...
...الذي صار إمبراطورًا قبل عامٍ مضى
He recruited powerful subordinates during the raid on Impel Down two years ago,
،لقد جنّد بعض الأعوان الأقوياء عندما أغار على إمبل داون قبل عامين
and now has gained control over Pirate Island, Beehive.
كما أحكم سيطرته الآن على جزيرة القراصنة هاتشينوس
He's still extending his influence, filling Whitebeard's void!
!ما زال يواصل فرض سيطرته آخذًا مكان اللّحية البيضاء
The commodore of the Blackbeard Pirates,
،عميد قراصنة اللحية السوداء
Marshall D. Teach!
!مارشال دي تيتش
2,247,600,000 berries!
!ملياران و247 مليونًا و600 ألف بيري
Next up,
،تاليًا
he has only been called an Emperor for six years...
...صار إمبراطورًا قبل ستة أعوام فحسب
He's the youngest of the four and deeply trusted by his subordinates...
...إنّه الأصغر سنًّا من بينهم الأربعة ويتمتع بثقة عمياء من أعوانه
Beckman.
.بيكمان
Roux.
.رو
Yasopp.
.ياسوب
His top officers gained notoriety individually,
،اكتسب كبار قادته سمعة كلّ على حدّة
and with a high average bounty, his undefeated crew is the most well-rounded of them all.
...ومجموعته الّتي لا تُهزم لديها معدّل مكافآت مرتفع وأفضل توازن بين أيّ مجموعة أخرى
The chief of the Red Hair Pirates,
...زعيم قراصنة أحمر الشعر
Red-Haired Shanks!
!شانكس أحمر الشعر
4,048,900,000 berries!
!أربعة مليارات و48 مليونًا و900 ألف بيري
Next...
،ونُكمل
As a child, this natural-born monster laid waste...
...إنّها وحش بالفطرة يُزعم أنّها دمّرت قرية إلباف عندما كانت طفلة
She only trusts her blood relatives
...لا تثق إلاّ في أقاربها وأبنائها الخمسة والثّمانين، بنَت هذه الملكة المستبدة توتولاند
the queendom made of candy!
!مملكةُ مشيَّدةُ من الحلوى
The captain of the Big Mom Pirates,
!قبطانة قراصنة بيغ مام
Charlotte Linlin!
!شارلوت لينلين
4,388,000,000 berries!
!أربعة مليارات و388 مليون بيري
Lastly, during his time with the old Rocks Pirates,
.وبعدهما، كان عضوًا في قراصنة الروكس القدماء
he was just an apprentice pirate...
...لكنه ما كان إلا قرصانًا متدربًا
But thereafter, he earned the respect of vicious pirates through strength alone,
،ولكن بعد ذلك، حاز على احترام قراصنة متوحّشين بقوّته فحسب
and attained the title of Emperor!
،وانتهى به المطاف بحمل لقب الإمبراطور
The viceroy of the Beast Pirates,
،القائد الأعلى لقراصنة الوحوش
Kaido, King of the Beasts!
!ملك الوحوش كايدو
4,611,100,000 berries!
!أربعة مليارات و611 مليونًا و100 ألف بيري
I feel depressed...
...أشعر بالاكتئاب
Due to the decision at the Reverie, we can't deploy the Seven Warlords to fight the Four Emperors anymore!
،«حسبما قُرّر في مؤتمر «ليفيلي
Whether removing that poison was correct or not...
...سواء كان تخلُّصنا من ذلك السّمّ صوابًا أم لا
is up to how well the SSG, the Navy's Special Science Group, performs.
.«فالأمر منوط بمدى نجاعة مجموعة البحريّة العلميّة الخاصّة «م غ خ
For your reference,
،ومرجعًا لكم
here are the bounties of other legendary figures!
!إليكم مكافآت شخصيات أسطوريّة أخرى
The captain of the Whitebeard Pirates,
،قبطان قراصنة اللّحية البيضاء
Edward Newgate!
!إدوارد نيوغيت
5,046,000,000 berries!
!خمسة مليارات و46 مليون بيري
The captain of the Roger Pirates,
،قبطان قراصنة روجر
the King of the Pirates, Gold Roger!
،ملك القراصنة غولد روجر
5,564,800,000 berries!
!خمسة مليارات و564 مليونًا و800 ألف بيري
No pirates have ever surpassed these two...
...لم يستطع أيّ قرصان تجاوزهما
but once Kaido and Big Mom's alliance is formed,
،لكن بمجرّد تحالف كايدو وبيغ مام
the sum of their bounties will easily top those numbers!
!فإنّ مجموع مكافآتهما سيتغلّب على هذه الأرقام بالتأكيد
Right now, in the unaffiliated Wano Country–
...لكن حاليًّا في بلاد وانو الّتي لا تتبع للحكومة
Fleet Admiral Sakazuki!
!المشير ساكازوكي
Forget about Wano!
!انسَ أمر بلاد وانو
We don't have any resources available to send on its behalf,
!إننا نفتقر للقوة العسكرية اللازمة لتولّي أمرها يا سينغوكو-سان
Of course, I wasn't intending on getting involved...
...لا نية لي بالتدخل طبعًا
I was just providing these young Marines with the knowledge of a veteran.
.كنتُ أورث معرفتي مع الجنود اليافعين بصفتي جندي عجوز
Pirates share histories as well.
.حتّى القراصنة لديهم علاقات إنسانية
Those relationships influence their actions.
.كما أن لديهم أسباب لتحرّكاتهم
We can't predict their movements if we ignore their pasts.
لن ترى المستقبل إن جهلت التاريخ
Oh, yeah...
...صحيح
There was a pirate from Wano who was favored by Whitebeard, Roger, and Red Hair.
.أتذكر أن قرصانًا من بلاد وانو حاز على إعجاب اللحية البيضاء وروجر وأحمر الشعر
You mean Kozuki Oden?
أتعني كوزكي أودين؟
The man who once served as a commander on Whitebeard's ship...
الرجل الذي كان قائدًا في طاقم اللحية البيضاء قبل زمن بعيد؟
Oden was later recruited by Roger and accompanied him on his final voyage.
...انضمّ أودين لاحقًا إلى روجر ورافقه في آخر رحلاته
I can't imagine Oden has anything to do with this mess...
...من المستحيل أنّ لأودين علاقة بما يحدث الآن
but why do all these big-time pirates who disrupt the world...
...لكن لماذا هؤلاء القراصنة الكبار الّذين يؤرقون العالم
always get involved with Wano?
مرتبطون دائمًا مع بلاد وانو؟
I think it's too much to be a coincidence...
...أجد الأمر أكبر من محض مصادفة
Sakazuki!
!يا ساكازوكي